

stefan boghean@yahoo.com

+373 78352950

Profile

Versatile and passionate front end engineer with a great work ethic, known for meticulous attention to detail. I believe in building software that solves real issues and focuses on good user experience. My experience spans over 6 years in front end development and more than 9 years overall in tech industry - during which I've been working on various projects in e-commerce, building internal tools and complex visual website-builders.

My main expertise is with Typescript, JavaScript and React JS. Have experience with Node JS and PHP too. However, I believe that the tech stack that we use is no more than just a set of tools used for building great software - and for the goal of building great software - any technology, patterns or methodology can be mastered. The basics are the only things that should stand out.

Can lead, mentor and teach and I welcome any challenge.

Employment History

Senior Frontend Engineer, Grid Dynamics

May 2024 — Present

Grid Dynamics is a leading IT Services and IT consulting firm, working with some of the biggest clients in the retail, technology and financial sectors.

As a member of the Grid Dynamics team, my responsibilities include:

- · Working on a few projects the for Home Depot the largest home improvement retailer in the United States. Some of the technologies I work with here include TypeScript, React JS, Redux Toolkit, Vitest/React Testing Library and Node JS.
- Conducting technical interviews for frontend positions and internship roles.
- Helping other developers become more efficient and excel in their respective roles.

Notable achievement while working as a Senior Frontend Engineer at Grid Dynamics

While working as a contractor for Home Depot, the largest US home improvement retailer in the US, was able to fully familiarize myself with the team and the project, as well as the project's related processes and became the top performer within the team in terms of tasks completed all within a space of two months.

During my time at Grid Dynamics I also got certified as an Associate Cloud Engineer by Google Cloud.

Frontend Developer, Pixieset, Pixieset

June 2021 — May 2024

Worked on awesome projects and delivered the best possible user experience to 100k+ clients.

Pixieset offers tools for photographers to easy share, deliver and sell their work to clients. The main products include a client gallery delivery service and a website/portfolio builder for photographers to highlight and sell their work.

In my role at Pixieset, I mostly:

- Specialized in utilizing TypeScript and React to create exceptional user experiences.
- Primary responsibility was the development and maintenance of a flexible and dynamic visual page builder called the Flex Editor.
- Collaborated with a cross-functional team to translate design concepts into a functional and visually appealing modern content-creation tool.
- Performed daily code reviews, wrote technical documentation and on-boarded new team members.
- Worked closely with designers and backend developers to implement responsive and intuitive user interfaces.
- · Worked with Agile methodology

Notable achievement while working as a Frontend Developer at Pixieset

The highlight of my time spent as a Frontend Developer at Pixieset is the Flex Editor - a flexible drag-and-drop website builder for designing and creating beautiful and dynamic web pages.

Since I assuming this particular role I have fully embraced TypeScript, incorporating it as a fundamental component of my preferred coding technologies.

Full Stack Developer, Flothemes

September 2018 — June 2021

As a Full Stack developer at Flothemes:

- Developed and maintained a wide range of products, including premium WordPress themes, diverse plugins, and a sophisticated drag-and-drop design tool for webpage creation.
- Created REST APIs to manage user data and developed and implemented internal tools for automation and client support management systems.
- Ensured the maintenance and regular updates of company wide range of products, keeping them up to date with industry standards and user needs.
- Technologies I worked with here mostly included JavaScript and React JS, jQuery, SCSS, PHP, git, AWS.

Notable achievement while working as a Full Stack developer at Flothemes

The highlight of my experience as a Full Stack developer at Flothemes was Flex Block - a fully customizable and easy to use drag-and-drop design tool in form of a WordPress plugin, used for creating custom and dynamic web-pages. Flex Block project eventually transitioned into Pixieset's Flex Editor, which is an even more enhanced version of the tool which I'm also proud to be involved in.

As a **Technical Support Engineer at Flothemes** (for roughly 8 months before being promoted to a full-stack development role):

- Provided high-quality technical support to the company's clients, primarily photographers, assisting them in the creation and maintenance of their websites utilizing the company's products and services.
- Day-to-day work mostly consisted of solving server-side technical issues, implementing and integrating custom functionality and 3rd party API's and services, developing custom design for web-pages and Ecommerce stores.

- Resolved client inquiries and issues promptly and effectively, addressing technical challenges, and offering guidance on optimizing their website's performance.
- Demonstrated expertise in troubleshooting and problem-solving, ensuring client satisfaction and fostering long-term relationships.

Notable achievement while working as a Technical Support Engineer

While working as a technical support engineer at Flothemes, I fully developed a internal automation tool for efficient triaging, sorting, and managing user requests and technical tickets. This tool eventually streamlined the support process and contributed to an overall reduction in response time and an increase in overall support team productivity.

WordPress Developer, Enspire

May 2018 — September 2018

As an WordPress developer at Enspire:

- Successfully completed custom projects for medium-sized businesses globally, hosted on WordPress
- · Specialized in creating and enhancing customized web-pages
- Executed projects based on predetermined design specifications
- · Provided ongoing maintenance and support services post-project completion

Technical Support Engineer, ThemeFuse

February 2016 — May 2018

As a Technical Support Engineer at Themefuse:

- Delivered technical support to clients of the company
- Resolved various technical issues faced by users, particularly related to premium theme and plugin installations, as well as WordPress-related problems
- · Conducted product testing to identify and address bugs and other issues
- Gathered feedback from clients and generated ideas and suggestions to enhance the product's functionality and user experience

Education

Degree of Licentiate in Computer Science, Technical University of Moldova

September 2012 — June 2015

Studied a variety of subjects related to Computer Science, including:

- Web programming
- Computer Programming
- · Data Structures and Algorithms
- General Linguistics
- Computational Linguistics
- · Computer Networks

Links

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Credly</u> <u>Medium</u> <u>Website</u>

Skills

TypeScript JavaScript

React Js	HTML5/CSS3
CSS Preprocessors	Vue JS
jQuery	Node.js
РНР	Git
React Testing Library/Jest/Vitest	
Languages	
English	Romanian
Russian	

Project Highlights

One project that I would like to highlight and one that is commercially available is the <u>Flex Editor</u>, a project I've worked on and have been an integral part of while working at Pixieset.

<u>Flex Editor</u> is a flexible and easy to use web development tool that allows users to create web-pages with professional design without the need for coding or technical expertise. It is based and inspired on the project with the same name previously developed for Flothemes which I also worked on.

The editor is available and can be tested for free at https://pixieset.com/website/

Certifications

Associate Cloud Engineer Certification by Google Cloud.

https://www.credly.com/badges/67ddbbc1-05e5-4464-bdde-33548b148bdf/